Machel Slack Tel: 07880900087, machel slack@yahoo.co.uk

PERSONAL PROFILE

As an experienced Web / Applications Developer, my ability to communicate with clients and my meticulous approach to work, has allowed me to build and retain long lasting customer relationships which has resulted in repeat business for my own business. Additionally, my ability to rapidly acquire new software skills and to work with new technologies has allowed me to be proficient in building front-end interfaces using JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

I would now like to utilise the skills and experience gained from my seven years in Technology from University, and three years developing commercially, to undertake an entry level role within your company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

January 2016 - Present Web / Applications Developer Team Lead, UK, Sinopia Inn Limited

Having completed IT projects for this brand, I was asked to work, part time as Team Lead to coordinate the work needed to execute IT projects.

Duties

- Supervised a small team of graphic designers by delegating tasks and monitoring work completed using Git Hub version control software to manage web and mobile applications development within a project environment
- Analysed stakeholder requirements using agile software development methodologies to design and develop features of web and mobile applications.
- Engaged with stakeholders to communicate project deliverables.

July 2012 - January 2016 Web / Applications Developer, UK, Unified Digital Media

I started by using Linux, Apache, MySQL and PHP (L.A.M.P) stack to design and develop websites with basic functionality as required by the user. I then went on to enhanced the users' experience by redesigning websites using MongoDB, Express JS, Angular. JS and Node JS (the M.E.A.N stack). I also carried out the planning of digital marketing campaigns that include the use of Bootstrap to design and develop mobile responsive WordPress websites, to increase awareness of a hotel brand. Additionally, I have worked on projects to increase customer base, by developing smart phone applications that engage users across multiple touch points; and created opportunities for improved revenue by developing WordPress plugins and widgets for commercial distribution.

Duties

- Designed and developed web pages with HTML5 and CSS3 to pique users interest
- Carried out C.R.U.D operations on SQL and NoSQL databases using AngularJS RESTful web service to manage business records
- Designed and developed beta version smart phone applications, using Objective C and Java to increase audience reach
- Monitored and controlled iterations of beta application, using open source version control software
 GIT to ensure efficient communication of project scope to project members

- Wrote code, using object-oriented programming, with PHP to create plugins for WordPress websites and improve revenue through commercial distribution
- Improved responsiveness of website, using AngularJS RESTful web service to request product information
- Parsed SQL and NoSQL records using JSON to update user interfaces
- Carried out cross browser development using Bootstrap to reach more users by designing and developing User Interfaces to adapt to the size of different browsers
- Carried out Behavioural Driven Development (BDD) using Mocha.js to reduce the number of errors while developing web applications
- Carried out Test Driven Development (TDD) using Jasmine.js to reduce the number of errors while developing web applications

EDUCATION

September 2010 – November 2011 Kingston University

MSc Accounting and Finance (pass),

September 04–June 08 Kingston University

BSc (Hons) Business Science with Computing (2:1)

Modules studied include: Fundamental programming concepts, Object-Oriented programming with Java, HTML Programming and Internet tools, Business Modelling, Web Technologies, Databases, Software Development with Java, XML for the web, Basic Visual Basic Programming, Advanced Visual Basic Programming, Systems Analysis and Design, Business Environment, Organisational Studies, Human Resource Management, Marketing Management, Accounting in Business Context, Business to Business Marketing, Decision Making, Corporate Strategy and Management Accounting

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Express JS, Node JS, MongoDB, NoSQL, JSON, XML, AJAX, Mocha.JS, Jasmine.JS, XHTML, PHP, MySQL, jQuery, GitHub, Objective C, Sublime Text Editor 2, Android SDK, Xcode, Eclipse and Adobe Creative Suite

ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Institute

PMI Agile Certified Practitioner (PMI-ACP) (pending)

INTEREST AND HOBBIES

Food and travel. I am currently writing articles for lifestyle blog being hosted by hotel brand Sinopia Inn

Portfolio

http://machelslack.tumblr.com